Guide to the Francis Marion Ownbey Papers 1934-1974
Washington State University Libraries Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections
Francis Marion Ownbey Papers
1934-1974
Washington State University Libraries, Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections Pullman, WA 99164-5610 USA (509) 335-6691 https://libraries.wsu.edu/masc/ mascref@wsu.edu
Cage 320
Ownbey, Marion, 1910-1974
35 containers. 17.5 linear feet of shelf space. 11,000 items.
18 ft. Summary Correspondence, research notes and drafts relative to taxonomic and genetic research, especially of the genera Allium, Calochortus and Tragopogon. A large portion of the papers are concerned with Ownbey's observations of the genetic behavior of the species of Tragopogon, and his discovery of the apparent evolution of new species under natural conditions through the mechanism of chromosomal doubling. Significant correspondents include: Edgar Anderson, Lincoln Constance, Arthur Cronquist, Charles Heiser, C. Leo Hitchcock, Phillip Munz, Gerald Ownbey, and G. Ledyard Stebbins, Jr.
A native of Missouri, Marion Ownbey was one of three twentieth century Ownbeys associated with plant taxonomy, the others being his brother Gerald Ownbey and his wife Ruth Peck Ownbey. His botanical education began at the University of Wyoming and its Rocky Mountain Herbarium and continued at Washington University in St. Louis and the associated Missouri Botanical Garden. Major influences on the early parts of his education were Aven Nelson and J. M. Greenman, two older taxonomists whose methods stressed close study of the details of plants, especially of dried specimens, and careful and precise organization of the knowledge of those plants. Their approach had been especially useful in criticising and revising the original description of North American flora, a development in which both had also participated. Though their approach was similar to that long used by botanists, it tried the patience of many, who could see no relation between modern science and the dried plant collections of the "haymaker" botanists, as they were derisively called. Moreover, their field had been much vexed by a troublesome and perhaps needless debate over the rules of botanical nomenclature. Nevertheless, by the 1920s and 1930s American taxonomists had essentially completed a catalog of North American plants and were well into a cycle of critical revision. This revisionary cycle consisted largely of a long sequence of "monographed genera." By the 1920s, this expression had come to mean the extensive and comprehensive examination of all literature and herbarium specimens of particular genera, resulting in lengthy and exhaustive monographic publications, then considered the mark of competence as a plant taxonomist. In this milieu, Ownbey began his career as a botanist. Not surprisingly he began with an attempt to study and revise Castellija, an extensive and complex genus which other taxonomists had worked with for years without producing a definitive statement.
Ownbey encountered difficulties with his effort to become the authoritative specialist on Castellija, and not until much later in his life did he complete his Castellija project. Yet it was not simply problems with this genus which marked his early career, but problems with the whole approach of plant taxonomy, and the influence of a newer means for approaching this science. This influence had come into the Missouri Botanical Garden in the person of Edgar Anderson, a geneticist who had, as he put it, invaded the field of plant taxonomy in search of an explanation of the mechanisms of the evolution of species. Anderson appeared to offer a newer philosophy for taxonomy, a field which seemed to be in need of such. He called for a combination of genetics, cytology and taxonomy, with a considerable influence of such diverse fields as paleontology, archaeology, anthropology and history also represented in his approach. Anderson's approach tended to stress common weeds and agronomic plants typified by the common road-side plants of the genus Tradescantia. (See Edgar Anderson, Plants, Men and Life (Boston: Little, Brown and Co., 1952) 16-30.) Ownbey may even have assisted briefly in the famous Tradescantia project.
Anderson's influence also appeared in Ownbey's adoption of the genus Calochortus as his primary field of investigation, for this genus featured many examples of the hybridizations and combinations of genetic materials which Anderson stressed. Calochortus, accordingly, became a life-long interest. A similar generic revision was added to Ownbey investigations in the early 1940s, shortly after he had become a botany instructor and herbarium curator at Washington State University. The second project concerned the genus Allium, a diverse genus containing both natural and domestic species and again much characterized by various hybridizations. Done in conjunction with a WSU cytologist, Hannah Aase, the Allium project combined traditional methods of plant description with root-tip chromosome counts and garden experiments. It resulted in a number of papers which constituted definitive revision of the North American species of this genus. In addition to these two projects, Ownbey began work on a general Flora of the Pacific Northwest with another Missouri Botanical Garden alumnus, C. Leo Hitchcock, who by the 1940s was at the University of Washington. Ownbey also participated briefly in a war-time botanical expedition seeking pharmaceutical plants in Ecuador.
Had Ownbey continued as he started he would have been known principally as someone who had revised hybridization-prone genera and as a contributor to a regional Flora. However, an almost accidental observation in the late 1940s took his career into a considerably different direction and into the project with which he became identified in his profession. This project concerned the genus Tragopogon, an introduced plant of the American West, some varieties of which had been used as a garden vegetable. This genus was prone to hybridization and Ownbey observed it informally for several years. He first commented on it in 1946 in a letter to geneticist Charles Heiser. But not until early June of 1949 did he make the discovery that he had observed the natural evolution of new species of Tragopogon occurring in his back yard. The first known observation of a species evolving in nature, Ownbey's Tragopogon study indicated that a chromosomal doubling had occurred without human intervention and an apparently stable species had appeared. His description to a colleague carried his sense of excitement about the discovery of the polyploid Tragopogon species:
"I have been having an exciting time this spring studying the origins of species in Tragopogon through natural hybridization and amphiploidy. We have three introduced species in the Palouse area which hybridize readily whenever any two grow together. The three Fl hybrids are highly sterile but give rise on occasion to three possible amphiploid. I have been observing the Fl hybrids between the two species for several years. This spring I found their amphidiploid and with this lead worked out the rest of the story. It is easily the most spectacular case that has yet been discovered. This would apply to the first case let alone its triplication." (Ownbey to Phillip Munz, June 28, 1949)
An informal paper on the genetic behavior of Tragopogon presented these observations in the spring of 1949. The following year a more formal presentation appeared in the American Journal of Botany, at which time Ownbey assigned names and published description of the two newly-evolved species of Tragopogon. Despite the publication of the species, Ownbey felt a degree of reservation about his findings. In later publications he expressed caution about the validity of the new species, although he continued to list them. Such, for example, was his practice in Vascular Plants of the Pacific Northwest, the regional Flora produced in cooperation with his associate Hitchcock and another collaborator, Arthur Cronquist, who joined in the project in the late 1940s.
Tragopogon tended to dominate the rest of Ownbey's botanical career. His initial article of the subject quickly proved to be a classic. More writing on the subject followed closely. Then in 1954, the investigation of further phases of Tragopogon won Ownbey a Guggenheim fellowship. The fellowship enabled Ownbey to spend a year in Europe examining historical Tragopogon specimens, as well as affording time to observe some species in their native area of the Balkan peninsula. It also enabled him to establish contact with Russian, Bulgarian and Turkish botanists, who offered to find specimens of the varieties of Tragopogon found in remote areas, principally within the Soviet Union.
Ownbey returned to the United States with much information about Tragopogon, though not enough to complete a global generic survey. For several years he sought to acquire the Asian species necessary to the task, but only over a long period of time did some material become available. Even the Russian correspondents had difficulty acquiring materials, as many of the species existed in remote areas of the Caucasus and Asiatic Russia, and, possibly, they had been discouraged from cooperation with a western geneticist. Consequently Ownbey's work with Tragopogon tended to take a more specialized approach. His greenhouse and garden plantings, accordingly, came to be used by himself and a succession of graduate students as materials for examination of very specific questions about genetic mechanisms.
In the later 1950s, Ownbey partly turned his attention from the Tragopogon project to production of Vascular Plants of the Pacific Northwest. Although this five-volume work came to be more the project of Hitchcock and Cronquist, two more traditional taxonomists, Ownbey's genetic insights had an influence. Working in close association with Cronquist, who was located in New York City, Ownbey proved he could also work in traditional manners. This approach also appeared in his contribution of the section on the genus Castellija, in which he "monographed" the genus with Greenmanian thoroughness.
Through the 1950s and 1960s, a constant series of small matters concerning Allium and Calochortus had been in the background of the more spectacular Tragopogon project and the regional flora. Also, Ownbey had been administering the University herbarium during all this time, as well as teaching classes in botany. By the later 1960s the herbarium and his teaching duties began to occupy greater portions of his time, and his research activity slackened. He died in December 1974 at the age of 64. Shortly afterward, the University herbarium was named the Marion Ownbey Herbarium as a tribute to him.
Marion Ownbey's papers consist of correspondence, research materials, drafts of writings, and field notes, all relating to his activities as a plant taxonomist and geneticist. The correspondence contains many extensive personal reflections on problems of plant taxonomy, on the revision of the genera Allium, Calochortus and Castellija, and on his classic observations of the genetic behavior of the genus Tragopogon. Research notes on all of these projects provide complementary documentation. Ownbey's papers also contain materials relative to herbarium administration, composition of Vascular Plants of the Pacific Northwest, and matters involving teaching and research at Washington State University.
The papers are arranged in three series, following Ownbey's original order with slight modification. The first, correspondence is arranged in a chronological sequence. The second series, research materials, is arranged according to projects, while the third, materials relating to teaching and faculty matters, is arranged by subjects.
This collection is open and available for research use.
The papers of Francis Marion Ownbey, Jr. (1910-1974) were transferred from the Washington State University Ownbey Herbarium to the Washington State University Library in 1975.
A print index to the correspondence in Series one exists as WSU MASC.
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Ownbey, Marion, 1910-1974 -- Archives; Constance, Lincoln, 1909-2001; Heiser, Charles B. (Charles Bixler), 1920-; Anderson, Edgar, 1897-1969; Hitchcock, C. Leo (Charles Leo), 1902-1986.; Cronquist, Arthur; Ownbey, Gerald B., 1916-; Munz, Philip A. (Philip Alexander), 1892-1974
Botany -- Classification; Genetics -- Research; Botanists -- United States -- Correspondence
Science; Agriculture; Washington (State)
The following section contains a detailed listing of the materials in the collection.
- Series 1: General Correspondence, 1935-1974; 8000 items.
  - 1935-1938 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1939 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Jan-May 1940 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - June-Dec 1940 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Jan-Mar 1941 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Apr-Aug 1941 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Sept-Dec 1941 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Jan-Mar 1942 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Apr-July 1942 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Aug-Dec 1942 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Jan-Mar 1943 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Apr-July 1943 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Aug-Dec 1943 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - July-Sept 1944 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Oct-Dec 1944 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Jan-Mar 1945 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Apr-June 1945 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - July-Oct 1945 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Nov-Dec 1945 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Jan-Mar 1946 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Apr-Aug 1946 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Sept-Dec 1946 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Jan-Apr 1947 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - May-July 1947 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Aug-Dec 1947 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Jan-Mar 1948 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Apr-June 1948 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - July-Sept 1948 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Oct-Dec 1948 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Jan-Mar 1949 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Apr-June 1949 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - July-Sept 1949 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Oct-Dec 1949 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Jan-Mar 1950 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Apr-June 1950 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - July-Sept 1950 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Oct-Dec 1950 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Jan-Apr 1951 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - May-June 1951 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - July-Sept 1951 (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Oct-Dec 1951 (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Jan-June 1952 (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - July-Dec 1952 (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Jan-Mar 1953 (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Apr-June 1953 (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - July-Sept 1953 (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - Oct-Dec 1953 (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - Jan-Apr 1954 (Box 7, Folder 49)
  - May-Dec 1954 (Box 7, Folder 50)
  - Jan-Sept 1955 (Box 7, Folder 51)
  - Oct-Dec 1955 (Box 7, Folder 52)
  - Jan-Mar 1956 (Box 7, Folder 53)
  - Apr-June 1956 (Box 7, Folder 54)
  - July-Sept 1956 (Box 7, Folder 55)
  - Oct-Dec 1956 (Box 7, Folder 56)
  - Jan-Mar 1957 (Box 8, Folder 57)
  - Apr-Sept 1957 (Box 8, Folder 58)
  - Oct-Dec 1957 (Box 8, Folder 59)
  - Jan-Mar 1958 (Box 8, Folder 60)
  - Apr-May 1958 (Box 8, Folder 61)
  - June-Sept 1958 (Box 8, Folder 62)
  - Oct-Dec 1958 (Box 8, Folder 63)
  - Jan-Mar 1959 (Box 8, Folder 64)
  - Apr-Sept 1959 (Box 8, Folder 65)
  - Oct-Dec 1959 (Box 8, Folder 66)
  - Jan-May 1960 (Box 9, Folder 67)
  - June-Dec 1960 (Box 9, Folder 68)
  - Jan-June 1961 (Box 9, Folder 69)
  - July-Dec 1961 (Box 9, Folder 70)
  - Jan-June 1962 (Box 9, Folder 71)
  - July-Dec 1962 (Box 9, Folder 72)
  - Jan-June 1963 (Box 9, Folder 73)
  - July-Dec 1963 (Box 9, Folder 74)
  - Jan-June 1964 (Box 10, Folder 75)
  - July-Dec 1964 (Box 10, Folder 76)
  - Jan-Aug 1965 (Box 10, Folder 77)
  - Sept-Dec 1965 (Box 10, Folder 78)
  - Jan-June 1966 (Box 10, Folder 79)
  - July-Dec 1966 (Box 10, Folder 80)
  - Jan-June 1967 (Box 10, Folder 81)
  - July-Dec 1967 (Box 10, Folder 82)
  - 1968 (Box 11, Folder 83)
  - 1969 (Box 11, Folder 84)
  - 1970 (Box 11, Folder 85)
  - 1971 (Box 11, Folder 86)
  - 1972 (Box 11, Folder 87)
  - 1973 (Box 11, Folder 88)
  - 1974 (Box 11, Folder 89)
  - enclosures, undated (Box 11, Folder 90)
  - Herbarium correspondence of Sherman Preece and Gwendolyn Wild, 1954-1955; 175 items. (Box 12, Folder 91)
  - University of Washington Press, business forms and related documents, 1962-1973; 30 items. (Box 12, Folder 92)
- Series 2: Research Activities
  - Research Reports to University Research Committee, 1951-1966; 150 items. (Box 12, Folder 93)
  - Notes and fragments relative to research projects, 1940-ca. 1960; 60 items. (Box 12, Folder 94)
  - Reprints of Ownbey's articles., 25 items. (Box 12, Folder 95)
  - Early, unpublished and preliminary papers, oral presentations, 1938-1965; 15 items. (Box 12, Folder 96)
  - Field Notebooks
    - Specimen Numbers
    - 28-227, 1934 (Box 13, Folder 97)
    - 228-403, 1934 (Box 13, Folder 98)
    - 404-494, 1934 (Box 13, Folder 99)
    - 494-1012, 1935 (Box 13, Folder 100)
    - 1013-1181, 1936 (Box 13, Folder 101)
    - 1251-1578, 1937 (Box 13, Folder 102)
    - 1601-1939, 1938-1940 (Box 13, Folder 103)
    - 2001-2377, 1940 (Box 13, Folder 104)
    - 2378-2518, 1941 (Box 13, Folder 105)
    - 2520-3091, 1942 (Box 13, Folder 106)
    - 3092-3367, 1947-1952 (Box 13, Folder 107)
    - 3368-3503, 1953-1969 (Box 13, Folder 108)
    - Ecuadorian Journal and Collection Notes, 1943-1944 (Box 13, Folder 109)
    - Chelan County, 1-153, 1947 (Box 13, Folder 110)
    - Journal, 1940 (Box 13, Folder 111)
  - Garden Books-Heald/Science Gardens
    - 1948 (Box 14, Folder 112)
    - 1949 (Box 14, Folder 113)
    - 1958 (Box 14, Folder 114)
    - 1959 (Box 14, Folder 115)
    - Garden, 1964 (Box 14, Folder 115b)
  - Minor Studies
    - Dicentra., 12 items. (Box 14, Folder 116)
    - Balsomorhiza., 10 items. (Box 14, Folder 117)
    - Liliaceae of Washington., 5 items. (Box 14, Folder 118)
    - Disporum maculatum., 5 items. (Box 14, Folder 119)
    - Gaillardia., 5 items. (Box 15, Folder 120)
    - Castellija of Idaho., 3 items. (Box 15, Folder 121)
    - Castellija of the Pacific Northwest., 7 items. (Box 15, Folder 122-23)
    - Survey of Genus Castellija., 125 items. (Box 15, Folder 124)
    - Polygonatum and Fritillaria., 10 items. (Box 15, Folder 125)
  - Calochortus
    - Collection record book (Box 16, Folder 126)
    - Planting record book (Box 16, Folder 127-29)
    - Planting record book (Box 17, Folder 130-34)
    - Hybrids (Box 17, Folder 135)
    - Calochortus of the Pacific Northwest., 52 items. (Box 17, Folder 136)
    - Cytological notes and drawings (Box 17, Folder 137)
    - Miscellaneous notes on Calochortus., 10 items. (Box 17, Folder 138)
  - Allium
    - Collection and accession record book., 5 items. (Box 18, Folder 139-40)
    - Garden record books., 4 items. (Box 18, Folder 141-44)
    - Record of crosses., 1 item. (Box 18, Folder 145)
    - Allium keys (Box 19, Folder 146)
    - A. aaseae (Box 19, Folder 147)
    - A. acuminatum (Box 19, Folder 148)
    - A. amplectens (Box 19, Folder 149)
    - A. anceps (Box 19, Folder 150)
    - A. brevistylum (Box 19, Folder 151)
    - A. brandegei (Box 19, Folder 152)
    - A. cernum (Box 19, Folder 153)
    - A. crenulatum (Box 19, Folder 154)
    - A. douglasii (Box 19, Folder 155)
    - A. elmendorfii (Box 19, Folder 156)
    - A. glandorum (Box 19, Folder 157)
    - A. gooddingii (Box 19, Folder 158)
    - A. fibrillum (Box 19, Folder 159)
    - A. hyalinum (Box 19, Folder 160)
    - A. kunthi (Box 19, Folder 161)
    - A. lemmoni (Box 19, Folder 162)
    - A. madidum (Box 19, Folder 163)
    - A. parvum (Box 19, Folder 164)
    - A. peninsularare (Box 19, Folder 165)
    - A. platycanle (Box 19, Folder 166)
    - A. schoenoprasm (Box 19, Folder 167)
    - A. simillimum (Box 19, Folder 168)
    - A. stellatum (Box 19, Folder 169)
    - A. tricoccum (Box 19, Folder 170)
    - A. tolmiei (Box 19, Folder 171)
    - A. validum (Box 19, Folder 172)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 19, Folder 173)
    - Allium chromosomes (Box 19, Folder 174)
    - Aeuminatum alliance (Box 20, Folder 175)
    - Campanulatum (bisceptrum) alliance (Box 20, Folder 176)
    - Canadense alliance (Box 20, Folder 177-79)
    - Sanbornii alliance (Box 20, Folder 180)
    - Obtusum alliance (Box 20, Folder 181)
    - Allium of the Pacific Northwest (Box 21, Folder 182)
    - Allium of Arizona (Box 21, Folder 183)
    - Allium of Idaho (Box 21, Folder 184)
    - Allium of Texas (Box 21, Folder 185-86)
  - Tragopogon
    - Tragopogon accessions list (Box 22, Folder 187)
    - Notes on the genus Tragopogon (Box 22, Folder 188-89)
    - Record book of specimens observed at Kew, Vienna, Firenze and Paris (Box 22, Folder 190)
    - Record book of specimens observed at De Candolle Herbarium, Bossier Herbarium and the British Museum (Box 22, Folder 191)
    - Record book of specimens observed at Geneva (Box 22, Folder 192)
    - Observation Notebooks
      - notes, 1949 (Box 22, Folder 193)
      - Fl, 1950-1951 (Box 23, Folder 194)
      - F2, 1952 (Box 23, Folder 195)
    - Garden Books
      - 1950-1951 (Box 23, Folder 196)
      - 1951-1952 (Box 23, Folder 197)
      - I, 1953 (Box 23, Folder 198)
      - II, 1953 (Box 23, Folder 199)
      - 1954 (Box 23, Folder 200)
      - 1955-1956 (Box 23, Folder 201)
      - 1957 (Box 23, Folder 202)
      - 1958 (Box 23, Folder 203)
      - 1959 (Box 23, Folder 204)
      - 1960 (Box 23, Folder 205)
      - 1961 (Box 23, Folder 206)
      - 1962 (Box 23, Folder 207)
      - 1963 (Box 24, Folder 208)
      - 1964 (Box 24, Folder 209)
      - 1965 (Box 24, Folder 210)
      - 1966 (Box 24, Folder 211)
      - 1968 (Box 24, Folder 212)
      - 1969 (Box 24, Folder 213)
      - 1972 (Box 24, Folder 214)
    - Greenhouse Books
      - 1953 (Box 24, Folder 215)
      - 1955 (Box 24, Folder 216)
      - 1956-1957 (Box 24, Folder 217)
      - 1958-1959 (Box 24, Folder 218)
      - 1960-1961 (Box 24, Folder 219)
      - 1962-1967 (Box 24, Folder 220)
      - 1967-1972 (Box 24, Folder 221)
      - Seed Record Book, 1956-1965 (Box 25, Folder 222)
    - Seed Fertility Count Books
      - 1952-1953 (Box 25, Folder 223)
      - 1953 (Box 25, Folder 224)
      - 1954 (Box 25, Folder 225)
      - 1956-1958 (Box 25, Folder 226)
      - 1959-1960 (Box 25, Folder 227)
      - 1962-1963 (Box 25, Folder 228)
      - 1964-1965 (Box 25, Folder 229)
    - Fertility Summary Data Book (Box 25, Folder 230-31)
    - Pollen Count Book, 1957 (Box 25, Folder 232)
    - Pollen Count Book, 1958-1959 (Box 25, Folder 233)
    - Laboratory Record Book, 1953 (Box 25, Folder 234)
    - Fixing, Sectioning, Staining Record Book, 1955 (Box 25, Folder 235)
    - Summary and Analysis Book, 1953-1954 (Box 25, Folder 236)
    - "14" (see No. 215) (Box 25, Folder 237-38)
    - T. dubius hybrids, notebook (Box 26, Folder 239)
    - T. porrifolius, notebook (Box 26, Folder 240)
    - T. orientalis, notebook (Box 26, Folder 241)
    - T. pratensis hybrids I, notebooks (Box 26, Folder 242-43)
    - S-I species, notebooks, 1963-1964 (Box 26, Folder 244-47)
    - Sinnatus Complex, notebooks, 1960 (Box 26, Folder 248-50)
    - Meiosis (Box 27, Folder 251)
    - Mitosis, notebook, 1951 (Box 27, Folder 252)
    - Mitosis, Tragopogon hybrids, notebook, 1951 (Box 27, Folder 253)
    - Mitosis, notebook, 1951-1952 (Box 27, Folder 254)
    - Mitosis, notebook, 1965 (Box 27, Folder 255)
    - Miscellaneous notes on Tragopogon, 1950-1960; 200 items. (Box 27, Folder 256-57)
    - Tragopogon Summary Sheets., 50 items. (Box 28, Folder 258)
    - Tragopogon Summary Sheets., 50 items. (Box 29, Folder 259)
    - Drafts of Tragopogon Articles, 1950-1963; 10 items. (Box 30, Folder 260-61)
    - Photographs, 1949-1960; 12 items. (Box 30, Folder 262)
    - Research support, 1950-1965; 50 items. (Box 30, Folder 263)
    - Tragopogon materials of Bert Brehm, 1965-1968; 30 items. (Box 30, Folder 264)
    - Tragopogon material of Ray Hoff (Box 30, Folder 264b)